# DONALD PARMINTER LOKONG

Nairobi, Kenya +254 719 762 808 donald.lokong@strathmore.edu

# Software Engineer

	•			
Λ	<b>L</b>			_
Δ	П	$\alpha$	ш	т

My name is Donald and I am 26-year-oldSoftware Engineer based in Nairobi, who is passionate aboutsoftware development and application security. I have an extensive knowledge various programming languages, engaged in significant software development projects and can demonstrate understanding of modern design patterns and frameworks.

# **Projects and Competions**

March 2018

My Safaricom App Improvement (UI/UX)

Safaricom LTD

An improvement of the Safaricom Application UI/UX design during a Safaricom Hackathon

- Seamless design screens
- Flow diagrams and data diagrams
- Elaborate wire-frames

February 2018 - Present Invoice Generator (React)

Personal Project

An Invoice Generating Application built with React.js with the following features

- Add and delete jobs
- Print invoices
- Generates a downloadable PDF invoice

Januray 2018 - Present Appointment Management System (Web App)

Personal Project

An elaborate Appointment Management System with these features

- Seamless payment of consultation fees
- Event scheduling to set up meetings
- Admin Panel to manage scheduled appointments

November 2017 -

Wish Foundation Website (Ongoing)

Present

Walk In Their Shoes Foundation

A charity organization website with the following features

- Portifolio and pictorial view
- Event scheduler and viewer
- Donation system integrated with Paypal

June 2017 - Present

Nyumbani Taxi Official Website (Online)

Nyumbani Taxi LTD

A taxi hailing company's official website

- Responsive design
- Customer interaction, signup and feedback
- Fare estimation system (ongoing)

March 2017

FKF (Official Site)

Football Kenya Federation

Football Kenya Federation official website

- League standings widget that automatically calculates standing according to scores
- An elaborate news service complete with social media interaction
- All leagues intergration in all men and women categories

Januray 2017 - Present ReenInTheCity (Wordpress Blog)

Doreen Kinyanjui (Fashion Model)

A personal fashion blog that enables posting of photos and articles in a chronological view

2016 - Present Portifolio Website (Online)

Donald Parminter Lokong

Fully responsive web application that demonstrates my skills as a Software Engineer

Hotel Management System (Java) May 2016 - Present

Personal Project

Java Based Hotel Management System that demonstrates use of servlets

- Room booking
- Food timetable scheduling
- Online payment

February 2015 - Present Event Management System (Java)

Personal Project

Java Based Event Management System

- Event booking
- Event Reservation
- Online payment system

## **Work Experience**

#### 2012 - 2013 Network Administrator

Spreenet Cyber Services

In charge of a medium sized networking environment with real-time traffic.

- Oversaw the design and implementation of computer networks based on the needs and available
- Facilitated network stability and connectivity.
- Improved problem solving and troubleshooting skills by working on a network setup of this scale.
- Improved on security techniques that would never have been gained in school.
- Interacted with different kinds of clients that aided in improved people skills.
- Manage configuration and operation of new client-based computer operating systems.

### **IT Support**

Tarime Suppliers LTD

In the front-line dealing with employees or customers with technical issues whilst being able to maintain local based systems.

- Installing and configuring computer systems.
- Diagnosing and solving hardware/software faults.
- Logging customer/employee queries.
- Maintaining website.

#### 2016 - Now System Administrator

### Nyumbani Taxi LTD

Overseeing a client based system that manages user usage and logs them in a cloud server.

- Monitor the system daily and respond to security and usability concerns.
- Manage configuration and operation of new systems.
- Provide technical support for both hardware and software queries encountered by users.
- Review application logs.
- Upgrade systems and processes to enhance functionality and fix security issues.

### 2013 - 2015

## Education

2006 - 2010 High School Diploma

Mangu High School

2016 - Present BSc. Bachelor in Business Information Technology

Strathmore University

Dean's Honors List

2010 - 2014 Networking

Computer Pride Center

• CCENT

• CCNA - Routing And Switching

• Understanding Cisco Cybersecurity Fundamentals (SECFND)

• Implementing Cisco Cybersecurity Operations (SECOPS)

### Skills

Full Stack Development

Data Structures and Algorithmsm, React.js, ES6 - JavaScript, MongoDB, Firebase, Express.js, web server (nginx, Apache), Git

Programming Languages

JavaScript, C++, Java, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, PHP, R Programming

Hardware Systems

Multiplexers, PC/Server, Admin, Routers, Switches, IP Telephony, Mac, Windows, Linux

Systems

Network Management

- Network Maintenance
- Network Security
- Network Troubleshooting

**Applications** 

Microsoft Office Suite, Wireshark, Metasploit, Adobe Photoshop, Sketch, Adobe Illustrator

### References

+254 721 788757 Steve Kayugira

Strathmore University

Data Scientist and Research

+254 738 448480 Preet Anil Taylor

*Nyumbani Taxi LTD*CEO Nyumbani Taxi LTD